A typhoon is coming soon.
Because of it, a landslide will occur.
Those five you are
so close with will all die.
Mr. Nishigami?
Let me tell you what will happen
if you break the code.
Every human involved with you
will have all Grim Reaper
related memories erased.
And of course,
you yourself will be punished
by the laws of the underworld.
Such a thing is impossible!
The typhoon passes through multiple areas.
Up on that mountain,
there is an old shrine nobody visits.
All natural disasters around here
are governed by that shrine.
If you go there, you may
be able to change something.
A Grim Reaper in human form?
A Grim Reaper…
Are you here to collect me?
I'm sorry.
I can't die. Yeah.
Because I'm a god.
Well now, what do you need from me today?
Who are you?
Japan is home to myriad gods,
and their origins trace back
to the nature worship of the Jomon period.
As for me, the wind, water,
clouds, rain, lightning…
I control all weather!
I am an ancient god of Japan!
The venerable Dragon God!
DRAGON GOD
Dragon God.
Yes, well…
That aside,
what is a handsome young Reaper
like you doing here in the mountains…
Oh, right.
There's a typhoon today, right?
You must be busy too.
I am sorry for the sudden visit.
I need to ask you a favor.
Okay.
Then, shall I at least hear you out?
What is it?
The landslide.
I want you to prevent it.
What?
Why?
There are humans I want to save.
Oh, I see.
Huh…
So those people are fated to die
in tonight's landslide?
Yes.
Five young humans
have been marked for death.
Those people haven't…
done much.
Really…
They haven't achieved anything at all.
But this summer…
many things happened…
at that villa.
I think,
throughout this vacation…
they all discovered something.
"I want to protect
those young people's future."
I guess that's what
you're trying to say, but…
That isn't something
a Grim Reaper should say.
But, I…
Look.
Today, without a doubt,
a landslide will occur.
You cannot change that absolute fact.
However, there is a place
that is safe from that disaster.
And I know where it is.
It's right here.
Hundreds of years ago,
humans built a shrine here
because it was a safe place.
Rain pours down hard
on the top of this mountain.
Then the flood comes rushing down.
However,
the water that comes out of the valley
above here splits into two directions.
And, what's more…
Look around here. It's all bamboo.
There is a bamboo grove.
It protects the ground.
They say bamboo roots
are all connected underground,
like a net.
So, this place is right on top
of a natural safety net.
Then…
Yes, exactly.
If you bring the humans here
before the landslide happens,
they will all survive.
Hey there!
Wait a minute.
Hey.
You're a Grim Reaper, right?
Are you sure you should be doing this?
It's fine.
I have already…
worked enough.
As expected, the calm earlier on the shore
was the calm before the storm.
It is very windy here now!
-Do not go outside during this storm!
-It sounds real bad!
-It's impressive.
-Please seek shelter inside!
The wind is getting stronger.
Yeah. It will be okay, right?
This house won't get blown away, right?
I think it's quite well built.
Just in case there's a blackout,
we have a flashlight!
But when its battery runs out,
let's kiss again, Rinrin!
-We have this lamp too.
-Oh, nice!
Camping stuff is so useful
for times like this.
I should charge my phone now!
Rinrin, here.
I should also move the stuff
in the fridge to the cooler.
I'll go check a few things.
We've got a problem!
What is it?
I just noticed we have quite a leak here!
-A leak? Wait a minute.
-Yeah.
Use these.
Yeah, okay.
Mr. Nishigami?
Everyone, let's get out of here.
We are going out in this weather?
-It's dangerous to stay here.
-Oh, no!
Rinrin, you okay?
-I can't get them on.
-Oh, I'm so wet!
They are hard to put on!
-The oranges!
-Hurry up!
The velcro… the velcro's not sticking!
They're being blown away!
Mr. Nishigami.
What are you doing? It's dangerous here.
What if something happens to you?
Mr. Nishigami!
Please, help me pick the oranges.
I…
have met you before.
Thank you.
Come on.
This place isn't safe.
Let's go.
Jeez…
He really went and did it.
This is going to turn into quite a storm.
No matter how much AI evolves,
it can't stop a typhoon.
Isn't it powerless?
This storm really
makes you feel the limits of AI.
I wonder if that villa is okay?
A direct hit on Tatsumi Town?
That villa was built
on a slope facing the sea.
I hope it isn't damaged.
DISASTER PREVENTION COMMITTEE
Oh, no! I'm soaked!
-Be careful! The rain is really pouring!
-I'm cold!
Everyone, get inside.
Tsumugi, hurry!
I thought I was going to die!
-Wow!
-It's safe here.
My grandma's ashes.
It's fine. We'll go back there
once the typhoon passes.
But…
I feel like I shouldn't leave them there.
I'll go get them.
What?
Mr. Nishigami!
It's raining hard.
Are you going down
that mountain path again?
Why…
Why do so much for me?
I…
have met you before.
Who are you?
Ms. Midori.
This summer
was the best vacation.
Thank you.
I…
I like you,
Mr. Nishigami.
Me too.
I like you, Ms. Midori.
And I probably will…
forever.
Goodbye.
Mr. Nishigami…
You came
to save me too, didn't you?
Yes.
Sorry for forgetting you.
Thank you, Mr. Nishigami.
For saving those children.
A Grim Reaper, saving humans…
It's the opposite
of what I should be doing.
But I feel like
the reason I kept being a Reaper
was to save them someday.
You gave them a second chance at life.
I'm sure they will do their best
to not waste it.
Goodbye, Mr. Nishigami!
The best vacation…
Thank you…
everyone.
What?
We…
You've done something terrible.
I erased those humans' memories.
Is this where the villa was?
The villa is gone!
No one remembers you anymore.
Is God telling us
that our vacation is over?
Why did it come to this?
Your human form has become grains of sand,
turned into sea foam,
and vanished.
Subtitle translation by: Nix S.